<resources xmlns:tools="http://schemas.android.com/tools">
    <string name="app_name">WOTC</string>

    <string name="start">Start</string>
    <string name="first">First Station</string>
    <string name="second">Second Station</string>
    <string name="Third">Third Station</string>
    <string name="fourth">Fourth Station</string>
    <string name="fifth">Fifth Station</string>
    <string name="sixth">Sixth Station</string>
    <string name="seventh">Seventh Station</string>
    <string name="eight">Eight Station</string>
    <string name="ninth">Ninth Station</string>
    <string name="ten">Tenth Station</string>
    <string name="eleven">Eleventh Station</string>
    <string name="twelve">Twelfth Station</string>
    <string name="thirteen">Thirteen Station</string>
    <string name="fourteen">Fourteen Station</string>
    <string name="fifteen">Fifteen Station</string>
    <string name="verse">We adore You, O Christ, and we praise You.</string>
    <string name="reply">Because by your holy Cross You have redeemed the world.</string>


    <string name="FirstReading">If the world hates you, know that it has hated me before you. If you were
of the world, the world would love what is its own. Because you are not
of the world, but I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world
hates you. Remember the word that I have spoken to you: No servant is
greater than his master. If they have persecuted me, they will persecute
you also.
(John 15:18-20)</string>
    <string name="PrayerOne">O God, to free us from sin and weakness your Son, Jesus Christ,
embraced his fearful passion and crucifixion. Strengthen us to our
baptismal resolutions by which we renounced sin and Satan, so that
through the passion of this life's sufferings we might rise to a new life of
joyful service free of all selfishness. Amen.  </string>

    <string name="medidate1">Jesus, most innocent, who neither did nor could commit a sin, was condemned
        to death, and morever, to the most ignominious death of the cross. To remain a friend of caesar,
        Pilate delivered him into the hands of his enemies. A fearful crime to condemn an innocent to
        death, and to offend God in order not to displease men!</string>
    <string name="response1">O innocent Jesus, having sinned, I am guilty of eternal death, but Thou
        willingly dost accept the unjust sentence of death, that I might live. For whom, then shall I
        henceforth live, if not for you my Lord? Should I desire to please men, I could not be your servant.
        Let me, therefore, rather displease men and all the world, than not please you, O jesus.</string>
    <string name="medidate2">When our Saviour beheld the cross, He most willingly stretched out his
        bleeding arms, lovingly embraced it, and tenderly kissed it, and placing it on his bruised
        shoulders, He, although almost exhausted, joyfully carried it.</string>
    <string name="response2">O my jesus, I cannot be your friend and follower, if I refuse to carry
        the cross. O dearly beloved cross! I embraced you, I kiss you, I joyfully accept you from the
        hands of God. Far be it from me to glory in anything, save in the cross of my Lord and Redeemer.
        By it the world shall be crucified to me and I to the world, that I may be thine forever.</string>
    <string name="medidate3">Our dear Saviour, carrying the cross, was so weakened by its heavy weight as to fall exhausted to
the ground. Our sins and misdeeds were the heavy burden which oppressed him, the cross was to
him light and sweet, but our sins were galling insupportable.</string>
    <string name="response3">O my jesus, You did bear my burden and the heavy weight of my sins. Should I then not bear in
union with you, my easy burden of suffering and accept the sweet yoke of your commandments? I
therefore willingly accept it. I will take up my cross and follow you.</string>
    <string name="medidate4">How painful and how sad it must have been for Mary, the sorrowful mother, to behold her beloved
her son, laden with the burden of the cross, What unspeakable pangs her most tender heart
experienced! How earnestly did she desire to die in place of jesus, or at least with him, Implore this
sorrowful Mother that she assists you in the hour of death.</string>
    <string name="response4">O jesus, O Mary, I am the cause of the great and manifold pains which pierce your loving hearts!
Oh, that also my heart would feel and experience at least some of your sufferings! O mother of
sorrows, let me participate in the sufferings which thou and thy son endured for me, and let me
experience the sorrow, that afflicted with thee, I may enjoy your assistance in hour of my death.</string>
    <string name="medidate5">Simon of Cyrene was compelled to help Jesus carry his own cross, and Jesus accepted his
assistance. How willingly would he permit you to carry the cross: He calls, but you hear him not;
He invites you, but you decline. What a reproach, to bear the cross reluctantly!</string>
    <string name="response5">O jesus! Whosoever does not take his cross and follow you, is not worthy of you. Behold, I join you
in the way of your Cross; I will be your assistant, following your bloody footsteps, that I may come
to you in eternal life.</string>
    <string name="medidate6">Veronica, impelled by the devotion and compassion, presents her veil to Jesus to wipe his disfigured
face. And Jesus imprints on it his Holy countenance: a great recompense for so small a service.
What return do you make to your Saviour for his great and manifold benefits?</string>
    <string name="response6">Most merciful Jesus! What a return shall I make for all the benefits you have bestowed upon me?
Behold, I consecrate myself entirely to your service. I offer and consecrate to you my heart, imprint
on it your sacred image, never again to be effaced by sin.</string>
    <string name="medidate7">The suffering Jesus, under the weight of his Cross, again falls to the ground; but the cruel
executioners do not permit him to rest a moment. Pushing and striking him, they urge him onward.
It is frequent repetition ot our sins which oppress Jesus. Witnessing this, how can I continue to sin?</string>
    <string name="response7">O jesus, Son of David, have mercy on me! Offer me your helping hand, and aid me, that I may not
fall again into my former sins. From this very moment, I will earnestly strive to reform: nevermore
will I sin! Thou, O sole support for the weak, by your grace, without which I can do nothing,
strengthen me to carry out faithfully this my resolution.</string>
    <string name="medidate8">Those devoted women, moved by compassion, weep over the suffering Saviour. But he turns to
them, saying: Weep not for me, Who am innocent, but weep for yourselves and children. Weep thou
also, for there is nothing pleasing to our Lord and nothing more profitable for yourself, than tears
shed from contrition for my sins.</string>
    <string name="response8">O jesus, who shall give to my eyes a torrent of tears, that day and night I may weep for my sins? I
beseech you through the bitter and bloody tears, to move my heart by your divine grace, so that
from my eyes tears may flow abundantly, and that I may weep all my days over your suffering, and
still more over their cause, my sin</string>
    <string name="medidate9">Jesus, arriving exhausted at the foot of Calvary, falls for the third time to the ground. His love for
us, however, is not diminshed, not extinguished. What a fearfully oppressive burden our sins must
be to cause Jesus to fall so often! Had he, however not taken them upon himself, they would have
plunged us into abyss of Hell.</string>
    <string name="response9">Most merciful Jesus, I return to you infinite thanks for not permitting me to continue in sin and to
fall, as I have so often deserved, into depths of Hell. Enkindle in me an earnest desire of amendment
; let me never relapse, but vouchsafe me the grace to persevere in penance to the end of my life.</string>
    <string name="medidate10">When our Saviour had arrived on calvary, He was cruelly despoiled of his garments. How painfully
this must have been because they adhered to his wounded and torn body, and with them parts of his
bloody skin were removed! All the wounds of jesus are renewed. Jesus was despoiled of his
garment that he might die possessed of nothing; how happy will I also die after laying aside my
former self with all evil desires sinful inclinations.</string>
    <string name="response10">Induce me, O jesus, to lay aside my former self and to be renewed according to your will and
desiire. I will not spare myself, however painful this should be for me: despoiled of things temporal,
of my own will, I desire to die, I order to live for you forever.</string>
    <string name="medidate11">Jesus, being stripped of His garments, was violently thrown upon the cross and his hands and feet
nailed. In such excruciating pains he remained silent, because it pleased his Heavenly Father. He
suffered patiently, because he suffered for me. How do I act in sufferings and troubles? How freftful
and impatient, how full of complaints I am.</string>
    <string name="response11">O Jesus, gracious lamp of God, I renounce forever my impatience. Crucify, O Lord, my flesh and its
concupiscences; scourge, scathe, and punish me in this world, do but spare me in the next. I commit
my destiny to you, resigning myself to your holy will: may it be done in all things.</string>
    <string name="medidate12">Behold Jesus crucified, Behold his wounds, received for love of you! His whole appearance betoken
love: His head is bent to kiss you; His arms are extended to embrace you; His heart is open to
receive you. O superabundance of love, Jesus, the Son of God, dies upon the cross, that man may
live and be delivered from everlasting death.</string>
    <string name="response12">O most amiable Jesus, Who will grant me that I may die for you, I will at least endeavour to die to
the world. How must I regard the whole world and its vanities, when I behold you hanging on the
cross, covered with wounds? O jesus, receive me into your wonderful heart: I belong entirely to
you, for you alone do I desire to live and die.</string>
    <string name="medidate13">Jesus did not descend from the cross but remained on it until he died. And when taken from it, He in
death as in life, rested on the bosom of his divine Mother. Persevere in your resolutions of reform
and do not part from the cross; he who persevereth to the end shall be saved. Consider moreover,
how pure the heart should be that receives the body and blood of Christ in the adorable Sacrament
of the Altar.</string>
    <string name="response13">O lord jesus, Thy lifeless body, mangled and lacerated, found a worthy resting place on the bosom
of your virgin mother. Have I not often compelled you to dwell in my heart, full of sin and impurity
as it was? Create in me a new heart, that I may worthily receive your most sacred body in Holy
Communion, and that you may remain in me and I in tou for all eternity.</string>
    <string name="medidate14">The body of Jesus is interred in a stranger’s sepulcher. He who in this world had not whereupon to
rest his head, would not even have a grave of his own, because he was not from this world. You who
are so attached to the world, henceforth despise it, that you may not perish with it.</string>
    <string name="response14">O jesus, Thou hast set me apart from the world; what, then shall I seek there in? Depart from me
deceitful world, with his her vanities! Henceforth I will follow the Way of the Cross traced out for
me by my Redeemer, and journey onward to my heavenly home, there to dwell forever and ever.</string>
    <string name="secondReading">And Pilate said to the Jews, "Behold, your king!" But they cried out,
"Away with him! Away with him! Crucify him!" Pilate said to them,
"Shall I crucify your king?" The chief priests answered, "We have no king
but Caesar." Then he handed him over to them to be crucified. And so
they took Jesus and led him away, bearing the cross for himself. (John
19:14-17)</string>
    <string name="ThirdReading">If the world hates you, know that it has hated me before you. If you were
of the world, the world would love what is its own. Because you are not
of the world, but I have chosen you out of the world, therefore the world
hates you. Remember the word that I have spoken to you: No servant is
greater than his master. If they have persecuted me, they will persecute
you also. (John 15:18-20)</string>
    <string name="FifthReading">And when they had mocked Jesus, they took the purple cloak off and put
his own clothes on him and they led him out to be crucified. Then they
forced a certain passer-by, Simon of Cyrene, coming from the country, to
take up his cross. They brought Jesus to the place called Golgotha, a name
meaning "the place of the skull." (Mt. 15:20-22)</string>
    <string name="SixthReading">"Lord, when did we see you hungry, and feed you; or thirsty, and give
you drink? And when did we see you a stranger, and take you in; or
naked, and clothe you? Or when did we see you sick, or in prison, and
come to you?" And answering the king will say to them, ''Amen, I say to
you, as long as you did it for one of these, the least of my brethren, you
did it for me." (Mt. 25:37-40)</string>
    <string name="NinthReading">I lie prostrate in the dust; give me life according to your word. I declared
my ways, and you answered me; teach me your commands. Make me
understand the way of your precepts, and I will meditate on your
wondrous deeds. My soul weeps for sorrow; strengthen me with your
words. (Ps. 118:25-28)</string>
    <string name="SeventhReading">It was our weaknesses that he carried, our sufferings that he endured,
while we thought of him as stricken, as one struck by God and afflicted.
But he was pierced for our offenses, crushed for our sins; upon him was
the punishment that makes us whole, by his stripes we were healed. We
had all gone astray like sheep, each following his own way; but the Lord
laid upon him the guilt of us all. (Is. 53:4-6)</string>
    <string name="EightReading">There was following Jesus a great crowd of people, and among them
were some women who were bewailing and lamenting him. Jesus turning
to them said, "Daughters of Jerusalem, do not weep for me but weep for
yourselves and for your children." (Luke 23:27-28)</string>
    <string name="TenthStation">They gave Jesus wine to drink mixed with gall; but when he had tasted it,
He would not drink. Then, after they had crucified him, they divided his
clothes, casting lots, to fulfill what was spoken through the prophet:
''They divided my clothes among them, and upon my garment they cast
lots.'' (Mt. 27:34-35)</string>
    <string name="EleventhStation">When they came to Golgotha, the place called the Skull, they crucified
Jesus and the robbers, one on his right and the other on his left. And Jesus
said, "Father, forgive them for they do not know what they are doing."
(Luke 23:33-35; John 19:18)</string>
    <string name="TwelfthStation">It was now about the sixth hour, and there was darkness over the whole
land until the ninth hour, And the sun was darkened, and the curtain of
the temple was torn in the middle. Jesus cried out with a loud voice and
said, "It is finished. Father, into your hands I commend my spirit." Then,
bowing his head, he died. (Luke 23:44-46; John 19:30b)</string>
    <string name="ThiteenthStation">When the soldiers came to Jesus, they saw that he was already dead so
that they did not break his legs, but one of them opened his side with a
lance, and immediately there came out blood and water. Joseph of
Arimathea, because he was a disciple of Jesus (although a secret one for
fear of the Jews), besought Pilate that he might take away the body of
Jesus And Pilate gave permission. (John 19:33-34,38a)</string>
    <string name="FourteenthStation">Joseph of Arimathea took the body of Jesus, and wrapping it in a clean
linen cloth he laid it in his new tomb, which he had hewn out of rock.
Then he rolled a large stone against the entrance of the tomb and
departed. (Mt. 27:59-60)</string>
    <string name="FouthStation" tools:ignore="StringEscaping">Now there were standing by the cross of Jesus his mother and his
mother's sister, Mary of Cleophas, and Mary Magdalene. When Jesus,
therefore, saw his mother and the disciple standing by, whom he loved,
he said to his mother, "Woman, behold, your son." Then he said to the
disciple, "Behold, your mother." And from that hour the disciple took her
into his home. (John 19:25-27)</string>

</resources>
